Contact

+447487248276

Email Me

a Lowestoft, Suffolk

GitHub

Portfolio Website

Instagram Profile

Skill Key Expert

Secured

Proficient

Intermediate

Basic

Testimonials

Kayleigh Hall

Development Manager

"Aaron has an eagerness to learn and develop his knowledge and tackle new challenges."

Faizel Desai

Project Manager

"Aaron has consistently shown his willingness to learn and his skills within web development. He is a hard worker who I believe will thrive in a growing web development team"

Aaron Smith

Junior Web Developer

Summary

Entry-level ICT Web Developer Full-Stack student with excellent ability within PHP, HTML, JavaScript (SASS – CSS3). Additionally, I have been attending the sixmonth long, award-winning Scion Scheme provided by the Netmatters company which trains web developers and software coders using in-house experts to provide invaluable workplace skills. Moreover, Netmatters has provided training in web and C# to a very high-standard of full-stack and back-end knowledge.

I am an analytical thinker with an ability to look holistically at a situation in order to find the best solution to identify problems and find solutions to address the situation. I can work well under pressure and adhere to strict deadlines.

Skills

HTML5 450+ hours

Several months of experience mainly personally. Comfortable with semantic markup and general structuring.

JavaScript 250+ hours

Able to use vanilla JavaScript as well as jQuery and AJAX. Comfortable with using external libraries.

Java 240+ hours

Developing fundamental objectoriented programming skills using the BlueJ and intelliJ IDEA environment.

Laravel 40+ hours

Understand how to install and manage the framework.

Jupyter Notebook 200+ hours

I have used Jupyter Notebook throughout my Data Science certification course with IBM.

CSS3 450+ hours

Able to manage layouts with both Flexbox and CSS Grid. Comfortable with using SCSS.

PHP 450+ hours

Basic knowledge of the language, including an understanding of the core features. Good understanding of both procedural and object-oriented PHP.

SQL 450+ hours

Knowledge of CRUD actions while working in PHP with phpMyAdmin. Moreover, I also used CRUD while working with C# using the Visual Studio and SQL Server environments.

Git 240+ hours

Used frequently while working on projects.

MVC (Visual Studio) and SQL Server working with C#, my coding also

includes OOP.

C# 200+ hours

Treehouse

Treehouse is an online learning community, featuring videos covering a number of topics from basic HTML to C# programming, iOS development, data analysis, and more. By completing courses users can earn points, allowing them to track their progress and see how much they've covered certain areas.

Total Score 15,087

https://teamtreehouse.com/profiles/aaronsmith26

Introduction to Scion Coalition Scheme

The Scion Coalition Scheme is an intensive, specially tailored training program being run by Netmatters in order to give willing candidates the opportunity to enter the industry as web developers. Under the supervision of senior web developers, scions generally aim to complete training within six to nine months. The course is intensive and therefore the level of learning achieved is extensive in a short space of time.

Experience

Riverside Business Centre

Financial Services Admin. 2020 - 2020

- Data entry including spreadsheets (Excel) and outlook.
- Experience working with SQL database queries including retrieving and updating information within the database.

Hoseasons

Inbound Sales Consultant 2018 - 2019

- sales consultant and first point of contact for customers to book their holiday. Responsible for handling inbound calls and booking holidays.
- Working on computer system, inputting customers' info/details i.e. holiday search & payment details.

Education

2022-Present

Scion Coalition Scheme

- Undertook an intensive, specially tailored training program under the supervision of senior web developers in the industry. This course is 40 hours per week and simulates employment as a developer to ensure the trainee is prepared for full time employment.
- Studied front-end and back-end development including UI/UX design, mobile development, object-oriented programming and databases.
- Working as an individual or as part of a team on projects and assignments; also helping other scions who may be struggling on a project. Moreover, as well as (and just as importantly) knowing when to ask for help for myself, so I can quickly resolve any issues I may have when working on a project.

2018-2022 East Coast College / Diploma Level 5.

- Diploma in Computing and Mathematics.
- Modules: Object-oriented Java programming, Algorithms, data structures, and computability, web technologies, mathematics.

2019-2020 IBM Data Science Professional Certificate.

 Building data science skills, learnt Python & SQL, analyzing & visualizing data, built machine learning models.

2016-2016 **Zend / PHP Training and PHP Certification.**

- PHP Fundamentals I and II.
- Create database-driven web applications, similar to the course applications. Coded object-oriented programming (OOP) techniques in my applications.

Hobbies

Data Science / Sports Analytics

I use Data Science (K-means clustering algorithm) to help design and develop my Fantasy Football Team. Moreover, I have designed graphic illustrations to highlight which players I should pick based on various factors.

Coding Video Games using C#

I subscribe to online courses using Udemy and Coursera to learn how to code small video games using the C# language. I enjoy the projects and materials available and take great fun completing coding challenges.